Friends, whenever we
take insurance for our vehicle, whether
we take it online or offline from an agent.
Friends, whenever we take a policy,
we get quotations from many companies and compare them to see
which company is good and which
company is bad?  Sometimes it is
called Tokyo.  And people also ask,
what kind of company is this?  How is its service?
How does it provide this claim?  What add-ons do you
get in it?  So friends, the
video we have brought for you today is
for this Eco Tokyo only.  This
company has been working in India since 2000.
Today it has been about 24 to 25 years.
This company works in all urban and rural areas.  The
company brings different products for you.
Now we will talk
about this company that if you get the
option of IFFCO Tokio then should you
take the insurance or not
and what is the feedback of IFF Tokio?
How does Echo Tokyo work?
What is the claim ratio of Iseko Tokyo?  How is the claim?
How is the service?  And we will talk
about this company.  So friends, before moving ahead,
subscribe to our channel
so that you keep getting notifications of such videos that we bring for you.
So let's get started.
This company has been working in India since 2000.
Meaning there is no problem in terms of experience.  I have a
very long
experience in India.
If a company has been working for 25 years and its
promoter has never changed till date.  Earlier also
IFFCO was with Tokyo.  IFFCO had it and
Tokyo had it.  Both companies are separate
and still have them for 25 years.  So the
company has a very long experience.  There
is no problem.  Talking about shares,
51% of the shares in Eco Tokyo belong to
IFFCO and 49% of the shares belong to
Tokyo.  So both these companies
work together in India.  IFFCO
is an Indian company and Tokyo is a Japanese
company.  Friends, if we talk about its
name, its name is Indian Farmers
Fertilizer Cooperative Limited.  Friends, those who
live in villages or keep coming and going from cities to villages,
you must have
noticed that you will find IFFCO boards everywhere
in the villages.  You will find
IFFCO boards everywhere in the markets in villages.
Because IFFCO has been
producing urea for farmers in rural areas since 1967 and it also
produces very good quality urea.
So this is a very old company and this IFFCO
together with Tokyo, the company
of Japan, Tokyo Marine Group, both of them
collaborated in the year 2000 and from the year 2000 till
now, both of them do
insurance work in India.  Let's talk about the
products, friends, you will get
all the products which any insurance
company, general insurance company
provides you, you will get almost all those products in India
like motor
insurance for your two wheeler,
car, commercial vehicle,
apart from that if you get tractor insurance, then all these will be included in it,
health
insurance, travel insurance, accidental insurance,
home insurance, business
insurance, workman compensation, marine
insurance, micro and rural insurance,
apart from that, Pradhan Mantri Fasal Yojana.  So
this company provides you almost all types of products.
So, no matter in which city you
live, you can take insurance from this company
because it has a
lot of insurance coverage.
They have a lot of products.  So, any product
that matches your needs, which
this company has, you
can buy any product for yourself from this company.  You will not face
any problem in service of the products of this company.
Now friends,
since we are going to talk
about car insurance, let us first talk
about cashless garage.  So
friends, you get Rs 4300.
You will find more than 4300 cashless accounts across India.  It
is a little less but
wherever you get cashless service, you will get
very good service there.  Talking about its claim
settlement ratio, it ranges from 92% to
97% and this is considered very good.  It keeps
varying in different years.
Talking about Zero Depth Policy,
you can take Zero Depth Policy from them for seven years
and if you do not have any claim in the seventh year, then
you
can take Zero Depth Policy in the eighth year also.  Number of zero
dup claims friends where big companies
like Tata AIG, ICIC LBD give you only two
claims in a year.  IFFCO
gives you unlimited claims on your vehicle.
You can take insurance and claim it for unlimited time.
Talking about renewal, keep getting insurance done till the vehicle
age of your vehicle, whether it is 10
years, 15 years or 20 years.
Talking about salvage charges,
5% salvage charge is charged.
That applies to all companies here as well.
Their service feedback is very good.
You will also come to know when you take the claim.
Its service is very good.
You will not face any problem in case of claim.
All the add-ons will be available
inside it.  As many add-ons as you need for your vehicle.
Policy Type Policy Type
You need the policy type you want, whether
you want comprehensive insurance or on damage insurance.  Do you need a third party policy or the
TP policy you get along with on-damage is
one year on-damage policy on a new vehicle or 3
years on-damage policy and 3 years TP policy.  So
you can get that also from this company here.
Now friends, let us see which
add-ons you can take.  Whenever you take a
comprehensive or own damage
policy for your vehicle and take a third party policy.
So let's talk about add ons.
What can you take with comprehensive and on-damage?  You will get zero dup.
Consumables Cover, Engine & Gear
Box, Tyre Cover, Return to Invoice, Battery
Cover.  If your vehicle is an EV or a
hybrid car, you will get a battery cover.
Along with this, if
your car is driven less then you can also take PaySU Drive.
Road Side Assistance No Claim Bonus
Accessories Cover.  If you are installing any accessories separately, be it
CNG or
electrical or non-electrical parts,
you are getting anything installed separately in the vehicle,
that can also be covered.  Loss of Personal
Belonging and Key Replacement.  Also,
if you are taking only third party then
you will get
PA cover of ₹15 lakh along with the third party.  Apart from that, you can take driver cover for
₹1 lakh or ₹1 lakh.  Along with this, whether
your car is five seater
, seven seater, eight seater, nine seater, six
seater, whatever your car is, you
can get passenger cover for all of them for ₹1 lakh or ₹1
lakh.  So if you are taking comprehensive
then you will get all these covers.   If
third party is included in comprehensive
then all these covers will also be available.
If you buy on damage then you will get only these ones
and if you buy only third party then you will
get these ones.  In this way you
can get coverage for your vehicle.  Whatever you
need, whether you want to take third party,
comprehensive, on damage
, you will get all the things here.  Now
friends, let us see that whenever you
take insurance for your vehicle, under
what conditions does the company
give you the claim.
You have taken insurance, but when will you
get the claim?  So when your vehicle gets stolen,
you will get a claim under vehicle theft.
You will also get your vehicle ID.  If it is a return to
invoice then
you will get the money for the new car in it.  Accidental
Damage: If your vehicle meets with an accident,
you will get a claim.  If the fire damage vehicle
catches fire, you will get a claim.
Personal Accidental Coverage.  The car met with an
accident.  Also, if the passengers
sitting in the vehicle or the driver get
injured, the company will
give you a claim for that too.  Natural Disaster Damage: If there is a
storm somewhere, a tree falls on your vehicle,
you are going to the mountains and a
stone falls from above, then in such natural
disasters, the company will give you a
claim for it too. Third Party Losses: If you hit
someone with your vehicle, you damage someone's vehicle, you
damage someone's property, you damage a person,
his parcel gets damaged, he gets
permanent disability, he dies, the
company will cover all these things for you. Along with this, if
rats enter your vehicle,
they cut the wires, the
insurance company will cover that too in your vehicle.
Now friends,
on which things will the company not give claim?  There will be a
claim for the things we just saw.
You will not get any claim here.  So what will
not be available?  Driving without a license.   If you
drive without a license, you will
not get any claim.  You will have to pay from your pocket.
Driver Negligence.  If the
driver's negligence is seen there.   If at the
time of a driving accident, it is
proved that the
accident occurred due to the driver's negligence, then
no claim will be made.  Substance abuse: If you drive after consuming alcohol
, drive after taking drugs
, use any intoxicant,
then you drive and it is
found in your body after an accident, then you will
not get any claim.  Mechanical Breakdown: If there is
any mechanical breakdown, you will
not get any claim because you
get the claim in case of an accident.  You are using the car daily.
Because of that some mechanical
breakdown is occurring in it.  So he will not
get it.  But in case of mechanical breakdown,
you will definitely get RSC service within
50 km from where your vehicle is.
This company provides you free roadside assistance service till .
And their road side assistance is also good.
You get the service easily.
Wear and tear is the same wear and tear
that occurs daily with the use of the vehicle.  You
use the car daily.  There are small dents there.
Your car parts are wearing out.  If
you want to claim them, you will
not get anything.  War: If there is any war going on,
suppose there is a war between India and Pakistan
or there is a war going on with any other country
and in that condition your vehicle gets
damaged then the company will
not give anything for it, it may give or it may not give,
both the conditions are there. Illegal
driving: If you do illegal driving then you will
not get any claim. If people below 18 years of age
drive then you will not get any claim. If you
drive on the wrong road, you
drive on the road where driving is not allowed, you
drive on the wrong side, you do
sports activities, then all this
comes under illegal driving.  So
no claim will be available here.  If any such
activity takes place with your vehicle and it is proved,
then forget about the claim, you will not get it.
No company provides it.
No insurance company will
provide all these things.  Neither will IFO give it to you nor is any other
company going to give it to you here.  Now
friends, let's talk about the charges that whenever
you take a claim or make some endorsement in the policy,
then
what charges will you have to pay?  So
if you take a claim then you will have to pay file charge of
₹1000 if your vehicle
is below 1500 cc and ₹2000 if your vehicle is
above 1500 cc.  Talking about salvage charges, you will have to
pay 5%.  You will have to pay 5% of the
parts that are changed in your vehicle after the accident.
Talking about consumable charges,
you may have to pay up to 10%.  But if
you add consumable add-on there, then you will
not have to pay for it.  Road Side
Assistance
50 Kms  It is free till then.  After that ₹25 to
₹50 per km.  You will have to give it.  50
km  It is free till.  If you go
10 km above that.  20 km  So he takes ₹25.  Some charge
₹35, some ₹40, some ₹50, it depends on
which area of ​​India your
car broke down in and
what charges the mechanic there is charging
from the company.  So accordingly he can take from ₹25 to
₹50 from you.  Talking about tyre depreciation,
whenever your vehicle's
tyres burst, either in an accident or while
driving on the road,
in both the cases the
company will not pay you the percentage of wear and tear of your tyre.  The company will calculate the
amount of rubber left in the remaining tyre and will make
the payment to you
there itself.  If you claim
your lost key, you will have to pay
₹250 as file charge plus GST.  If
you get CNG or LPG addition done in the policy, then
4% of the amount of CNG you have installed, say
50 rupees, then 4% of that
becomes ₹2000 for you, plus ₹60 for
your third party CNG, that will also be
charged to you here.  Apart from that, if
you want to add any electrical or non-electrical accessories in your vehicle policy, then the
company will charge you 4% for that also.  Whatever its
value, if it is Rs 1 lakh then the
company will charge you Rs 4000 plus GST.
So, whether you add accessories
or make a claim,
you will have to pay all these charges at that time.  Now friends,
where do you have to contact for customer support
?  Friends, their website
is www.fcotok.co.in.
All the information that I have given you will be
available here.  Apart from this, if
you need more information
about different products, then you will get all that information
here on this website.
Talking about the customer care number, this is
their number 18001035499.
You have to call on their number.  If you
need roadside assistance, if you want to
make a claim, if you want to
see nearby service centers
, you can call this number for that too.
By the way, if you go to the website,
you will
get the complete list of all the cashless garages there.  You
can see that.  So you can call here and also
check by visiting the company's website.
Talking about email, suppose you want to get
some endorsement done, then first
call the company's number and talk to them, if you want to
send them documents then you can do it here,
you can send the documents on this email ID,
apart from this if you have to make any complaint then
you can do that also by mailing on this email ID, from
here
whatever service you need, you will get all the services
from this website, through this contact number and on this
email and
friends let me tell you that this
is a good company in terms of service, you will
not face any kind of problem.   You can
contact customer care and you will get it.   Try
roadside assistance.
You will get very good service there too.   If you
go to the website, you will get all the details
about the company, whatever
work the company does, whatever products it makes available to you,
you will get all that.  So
friends, there is no problem about the company.  The
company has been working in India for 25 years
and is a good company.  You will mostly
see that when you buy a Maruti car,
Maruti gives you the IFFCO Toko insurance.
So you get cash there also.
Apart from that, if you buy any vehicle from outside, be it a
Tata vehicle or a
vehicle from any other company, you
get cash.  Try this once
because they have 4300 service centers which
are cashless.  So try to
find out your nearest buyer whenever you take its insurance.
If you are living in the city then you will
get it easily because there are many
service centres in the city.  There are 10 of them in the same city.
Like in Delhi,
you will find many in Delhi.  So there
is no problem there.  There is
no problem in Mumbai.  There is no problem in Pune.
So you don't have any such tension there.   If you take it
there, you will get it.  But
if you are taking a policy from IFFCO in a rural area, then
you must check it once at your nearest
service centre.  If
IFFCO is available and the premium matches yours
then take it.  There is no problem.
You will get the claim easily.  Meaning, just like Tata
provides you service, just like ICC LAD
provides you service, just like Libt provides you service
, you will get the same service from FCO.  There
is no need to hesitate at all.  You
can take this policy with your eyes closed.  You can take the policy of this company.  The
company never creates any problem in case of claims.
And let me tell you that there are many
service centre people who themselves
say that brother, get the insurance done through e-photo.  Do it
with someone else or not.  Do it with ePhoto.
Because they have cash tie up.
They know that the company easily
gives them money too.  The claim company will give it to you.   They will
give them DO and after giving DO, whoever
makes the payment to them, this also gives an idea about the
service of the company.
IFFCO gets very good feedback from many places.
He himself says that you should get insurance from Eco.
We have no problem.
So friends, this was my video
about IFFCO Tokyo car insurance.
Please let us know how you liked this video.
If you liked the video then please like the video.
Subscribe to the channel and
if you feel that the video is helpful
then you can share this video with your friends, your relatives and
your groups.
Thank you.